Guide to the Lucy Kroll Papers Relating to Lynn Riggs
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lucy Kroll papers relating to Lynn Riggs
1927-1972
YCAL MSS 826
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.42
(5 boxes)
The collection includes typescripts of Lynn Riggs's scripts and other writings; correspondence and subject files regarding Lynn Riggs and other Lucy Kroll Agency business associates and activities; Lucy Kroll Agency contracts and agreement files; and a small number of Lynn Riggs's personal items.
Kroll, Lucy
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lucy Kroll, 1995.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Lucy Kroll (1908-1997)
Lucy Kroll was born in Brooklyn in 1908. She was a literary and talent agent in New York, establishing her own agency in 1947. She represented numerous writers and performing artists including the playwright Lynn Riggs. She died in 1997.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes typescripts of Lynn Riggs's scripts and other writings; correspondence and subject files regarding Lynn Riggs and other Lucy Kroll Agency business associates and activities; Lucy Kroll Agency contracts and agreement files; and a small number of Lyn Riggs's personal items.
Arrangement
Organized into two groups: I. May 1995 Acquisition. II. November 1995 Acquisition.
Authors, American -- 20th Century; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century; Literary agents -- United States; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century; Literary agents -- United States -- 20th Century; Kroll, Lucy; Riggs, Lynn, 1899-1954; Lucy Kroll Agency
- May 1995 Acquisition, 1927-1985; 1; 4; (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged by type of material.
  Scope and Contents
  Scripts, correspondence and subject files, contracts and agreements, and other materials relating to Lynn Riggs and other business associates and activities of the Lucy Kroll Agency.
  - Typescripts of Lynn Riggs works
    - "An Affair at Easter" (novel), undated; 4 (Box 1)
    - "Borned in Texas" (play), 1930,1945, undated; 6 (Box 2)
      Includes typescript manuscripts, and corrected and uncorrected copies of play published as Roadside.
    - "Tropic Rhapsody" (synopsis), undated (Box 2)
    - "Verdigris Primitive" (play), undated (Box 2)
  - Personal items of Lynn Riggs
    - Notebook containing index of record album collection, undated (Box 2)
    - Leather key case, undated (Box 2)
    - Typed inventory of Riggs's study in Santa Fe, New Mexico, undated (Box 2)
    - Printed material, 1929, 1949, undated (Box 2)
  - Correspondence and subject files
    - Lynn Riggs
      - Copyright search 1985 (Box 3)
      - Production programs, 1932-1950, undated (Box 3)
      - Published forms: Knives from Syria, 1928 (Box 3)
      - Oklahoma! - rights, 1953 (Box 3)
      - "The Affair at Easter" novel, 1954-1956 (Box 3)
      - "All the Way Home" (Cherokee Night), 1956-1961 (Box 3)
      - Aughtry, Charles E., 1956-1960; 2 (Box 3)
      - "Love to Mamie" synopsis, undated (Box 3)
      - "Big Cake" - Sawyer Falk, 1960-1962; 2 (Box 3)
      - "Borned in Texas", 1954-1961 (Box 3)
      - Copyright folder, 1951-1955 (Box 3)
      - "Cream in the Well", 1960 (Box 3)
      - Current, 1959-1964; 2 (Box 3)
      - Lynn Riggs [production-related files], 1949-1952; 2 (Box 3)
      - Estate records, 1954-1958; 2 (Box 3)
      - Memorial, 1955-1962 (Box 3)
      - Obit (June 30, 1954) Variety, 1954-1964 (Box 3)
      - Lynn Riggs Players of Oklahoma, 1961 (Box 3)
      - "Out of Dust", 1949-1959; 2 (Box 3)
      - Publicity duplicate, lists of manuscripts, 1939-1954, undated (Box 3)
      - Properties, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
      - "Roadside"/"Borned in Texas", 1959-1967 (Box 3)
      - "Russet Mantle", 1957 (Box 3)
      - "Some Sweet Day", 1952-1966; 2 (Box 3)
      - Samuel French settlement, 1959-1964 (Box 3)
      - Television: "Someone To Remember", 1953-1955 (Box 3)
      - Kroll, Nathan [composer of music for] "Toward the Western Sky", 1945-1952 (Box 3)
      - "Laughter from a Cloud", 1947 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 1955-1985; 2 (Box 3)
      - Blank stationery, undated (Box 3)
    - Manuscript by Ramon Naya (poems), undated (Box 3)
    - "The Perennial Secretary" [typescript] outline for a television play by Ernest Pendrell, undated (Box 3)
    - "A Critical Introduction to the Plays of Lynn Riggs" [by] Helen Edwards, undated (Box 3)
    - Lynn Riggs manuscripts which may be given to the custody of the Riggs family and/or the Riggs Memorial
      - "Song in the AM", undated (Box 4)
      - "Some Sweet Day", undated (Box 4)
      - "All the Way Home", 1948 (Box 4)
      - "Laughter From a Cloud", 1947 (Box 4)
    - Production programs and blank stationery, 1927-1936, undated (Box 4)
    - Lucy Kroll Agency contracts and agreements
      - Dramatists Play Service contract with Lucy Kroll Agency and payments, 1951-1963 (Box 4)
      - Collaboration agreements, 1961, undated (Box 4)
      - Contracts on literary properties, 1954-1964 (Box 4)
      - Collaboration agreement for da Silva, undated (Box 4)
      - Authors League [Guild] - paperback and trade books, 1964 (Box 4)
      - Contracts - representation - services and material, 1962-1965 (Box 4)
      - English contracts (samples) for play deals, 1971 (Box 4)
      - Franchises, 1958-1966 (Box 4)
      - Foreign contracts, 1960 (Box 4)
      - French translators, 1970 (Box 4)
      - Translator's forms, undated (Box 4)
      - Society of Authors' Representatives - publishing contracts, 1966-1972 (Box 4)
      - Writers lists, 1952-1959 (Box 4)
      - Brown, David - Fox submissions [empty folder], undated (Box 4)
- November 1995 Acquisition, 2; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Correspondence between Lynn Riggs and Ramon Naya (Enrique Gasque) and others (Box 5)